{"1": {"question": "What is the lieder set work?", "correct": "Fruhlingstraum from Winterreise D. 911 by Schubert", "incorrect": ["Fruhlingstraum from Summerreise D.911 by Schubert", "Winterstraum from Fruhlingrreise D.911 by Schubert", "We Are Bulletproof : The Eternal by BTS (highly recommend)"]}, "2": {"question": "What does Fruhlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Dream of spring", "incorrect": ["Dream of summer", "Spring Day", "Dream of flowers"]}, "3": {"question": "What does Winterreise mean?", "correct": "Winter's journey", "incorrect": ["No More Dream", "Cold journey", "Lonely journey"]}, "4": {"question": "How many songs are in Winterreise and which number is Fruhlingstraum? (Respective)", "correct": "24, 11", "incorrect": ["14, 11", "34, 22", "24, 23"]}, "5": {"question": "What was a domestic factor in the development of the Romantic Lied?", "correct": "The growing availability and popularity of the piano and its presence in homes across a range of social classes.", "incorrect": ["The growing popularity of singing and availability of good teachers across a range of social classes.", "People's daughters transforming into ARMY fangirls, which led to composers panicking and introducing Romantic Lied.", "The decreasing popularity of Classical Lied among citizens which led composers to introduce Romantic Lied."]}, "6": {"question": "What was a factor in the development of Lied originally thought of by philosopher Johann Gottfried Herder?", "correct": "That language could unify all social classes, which sparked interest in lower classes.", "incorrect": ["That BTS would top the charts, so composers hurried to retain people's interest", "That music could unify all social classes, which sparked interest in lower classes.", "That language could only be appreciated by upper classes, which sparked an uprising in the lower classes."]}, "7": {"question": "Why did composers begin to focus on the piano accompaniment of Lieder?", "correct": "They realised the potential it had to support the text in a range of expressive ways.", "incorrect": ["They realised that it had previously had too great a role.", "They realised that BTS was too good at singing so they had to divert their attention to where they were not yet beaten.", "Their audiences were becoming dissatisfied with the piano part, so the composers had to adapt."]}, "8": {"question": "What is a song cycle?", "correct": "A unified collection of songs written to be performed in sequence.", "incorrect": ["A collection of songs written to be performed in a sequence of the performer's choice.", "A song with eleven unified parts to be performed in sequence. ", "A loop of the top ten BTS songs that plays ten times."]}, "9": {"question": "When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1838", "1848", "1997"]}, "10": {"question": "Who wrote the poem Schubert set in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "Wilhelm Muller", "incorrect": ["Suga", "Wilfred Muller", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe"]}, "11": {"question": "Schubert - What is a recurring idea in the text?", "correct": "The contrast between dreams and reality", "incorrect": ["The personalities of BTS members", "The contrast between love and loneliness", "The similarities between the narrator's past life and his dreams"]}, "12": {"question": "Which of the following is NOT a means through which composers unify song cycles?", "correct": "The songs are in the same time and key.", "incorrect": ["The songs are linked by explicit recollection of musical motifs between certain songs.", "There is often an implicit narrative thread.", "The songs are presented as musically independent numbers and the relationship is more implicit."]}, "13": {"question": "How does the changing music of Fruhlingstraum reflect its text?", "correct": "The 'happier' sections are symbolic of warmth and dreams, while the 'sadder' sections are symbolic of coldness and reality.", "incorrect": ["The slower sections are reflective of reminiscing dreams, while the faster sections reflect the poet's haste to focus on reality.", "The happier sections symbolise Schubert's love for Kpop, while the sadder sections convey Schubert's distaste for antis.", "The minor sections reflect the poet's old and harsh life, while the major sections reflect the great new life he has found."]}, "14": {"question": "What is the main subject matter of Winterreise?", "correct": "A poet who realises his destiny to always wander in solitude and perhaps never know love, companionship and rest.", "incorrect": ["A poet who must journey the world forever in search of something that does not exist.", "The hardships endured by BTS, which make international ARMYs sad because they can't help their oppas in Korea ðŸ˜¢", "A wandering shepherd who is lost and cannot find his way home to his loved ones."]}, "15": {"question": "Comment on how Schubert treats the piano accompaniment in Fruhlingstraum.", "correct": "It imitates not only concrete imagery but evokes a feeling far more powerful than the text could.", "incorrect": ["It creates implicit imagery and imitates the feeling created by the text", "It is barely heard as Schubert intended for the voice to be the prominent part.", "It is the prominent part, bringing out the main imagery and themes in the piece."]}, "16": {"question": "How has Schubert set the six stanzas of poetry used in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "ABCABC", "incorrect": ["ABBCBB", "AABCCB", "ABACAA"]}, "17": {"question": "How is the music in Fruhlingstraum used to assist the story in Section A?", "correct": "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the siciliana pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords.", "incorrect": ["Section A adopts a direct, folk-like style with the help of the melisma pattern, associated with beautiful and floral themes", "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the napolitana pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords.", "Section A adopts a direct, folk song-like style with the help of the florentine pattern which is associated with pastoral themes. The piano consists of gently rolling chords."]}, "18": {"question": "How is the music in Fruhlingstraum used to assist the story in Section B?", "correct": "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of short, sharp block chords. ", "incorrect": ["The tempo decreases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of sharp, chromatic chords.", "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of harsh and fast rolling chords.", "The tempo increases and the mode switches to minor. The piano consists of gentle block chords."]}, "19": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert write?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["Over 60", "Over 6000", "Over 2013"]}, "20": {"question": "Schubert - What are the metric qualities of the verse?", "correct": "It is written in iambic trimeter (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "incorrect": ["It is written in iambic pentameter (unstressed-stressed)", "It is written in iambic pentameter (stressed-unstressed)", "It is written in iambic trimeter (stressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "21": {"question": "How is the structure of Fruhlingstraum effective as a narrative?", "correct": "Quatrains A are about the poet's dreams. Quatrains B are about his sudden awakening to reality. Quatrains C evoke the poet's yearning to return to his dreams.", "incorrect": ["Quatrains A are about reality. Quatrains B are about his unpleasant dreams. Quatrains C evoe the poet's yearning to return to reality.", "Quatrains A are about the poet's dreams. Quatrains B are about his sudden awakening to reality. Quatrains C evoke the poet's haste to flee his dreams.", "Quatrains A are about the poet's "]}, "22": {"question": "Which of the following does Schubert NOT use to effectively contrast the three ideas in Fruhlingstraum?", "correct": "Changes of instrumentation and texture", "incorrect": ["Changes of style", "Changes of modality and key", "Changes of tempo and meter"]}, "23": {"question": "What is the role of the piano in Lieder?", "correct": "It is an accompaniment of equal prominence to the text that supports the ideas and feelings of the text in expressive ways.", "incorrect": ["It is the prominent part, overpowering the text and expressively creating the main feelings and ideas.", "It is an accompaniment of less importance than the text that has little musical value, occasionally chipping in.", "It is a part of equal prominence to the voice and it introduces all the themes while the voice supports the ideas and feelings."]}, "24": {"question": "Schubert - What does the siciliana pattern found in the 4-bar introduction NOT present?", "correct": "Images of mountainous landscapes", "incorrect": ["Pastoral themes", "Images of nature", "Folk-like musical 'image' to the audience"]}, "25": {"question": "Schubert - What is the intention of the iambic trimeter used in the text?", "correct": "To promote a folk-like simplicity and 'artlessness' to the text", "incorrect": ["To demote a folk-like simplicity and 'artlessness' to the text", "To promote a delicacy and 'artfulness' to the text", "To promote images of sophistication for the audience"]}, "26": {"question": "Schubert - What is the final foot in the first line of each pair?", "correct": "An amphibrach", "incorrect": ["An iamb", "A reptibrach", "A trimeter", "A nudibranch"]}, "27": {"question": "Schubert - Do the main points of stress remain constant in the text?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Yes except for one instance", "Only for one instance"]}, "28": {"question": "What is a melisma?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A kind of rhythm associated with folkish, pastoral themes", "A term used to describe singing one note per syllable", "A pair of notes sung to one syllable"]}, "29": {"question": "Schubert - How is the setting of the text?", "correct": "Typical of Lied: it is mostly syllabic and the rare melismas occupy no more than 2 notes", "incorrect": ["Typical of Lied: it is rarely syllabic and melismas are found abundantly", "Untypical of Lied: it is rarely syllabic and almost every syllable is a melisma", "Typical of Lied: it is all syllabic."]}, "30": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following is not represented by the major sections?", "correct": "Wealth", "incorrect": ["Dreaming", "Spring/warmth", "Love"]}, "31": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following is not represented by the minor sections?", "correct": "Poverty", "incorrect": ["Reality", "Winter/coldness", "Loneliness"]}, "32": {"question": "Schubert - How is the material written?", "correct": "Almost completely diatonic without modulation", "incorrect": ["Almost completely chromatic with much modulation", "Almost completely diatonic with much modulation", "Very well "]}, "33": {"question": "Schubert - How does the piano foreshadow the singer's line?", "correct": "In the four-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH", "incorrect": ["In the four-bar introduction by playing the melody in LH", "In the eight-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH", "In the ten-bar introduction by playing the melody in RH"]}, "34": {"question": "Schubert - What is/are the predominant key(s) of the song?", "correct": "F major and F minor", "incorrect": ["E flat major and E flat minor", "G major and G minor", "D major and D minor"]}, "35": {"question": "Schubert - Which of the following keys are not used as [at least] brief modulations?", "correct": "D minor", "incorrect": ["C minor", "B flat major", "E flat minor"]}, "36": {"question": "Schubert - What does the 'D' in D.911 mean?", "correct": "The catalogue of Schubert's works made by Otto Deutsch", "incorrect": ["A form of cataloguing created by Ottoman Deutsch", "Dani :))", "The catalogue of Schubert's works made by Otto Dutch"]}, "37": {"question": "Schubert - What does the '911' in D.911 mean?", "correct": "It is his 911th work, ordering chronologically", "incorrect": ["Jet Fuel conspiracy theories.", "It is his 911th individual song/piece", "It is his 911th work, ordering alphabetically"]}, "38": {"question": "What does Schnell mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Very fast", "Not too fast"]}, "39": {"question": "What does Etwas bewegt mean?", "correct": "With some movement", "incorrect": ["With much movement", "With very little movement", "With no movement"]}, "40": {"question": "What does Langsam mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Fast", "Not too slow", "Very slow"]}, "41": {"question": "Schubert - What keys were the song originally written in?", "correct": "A major and A minor", "incorrect": ["F major and F minor", "G major and G minor", "E flat major and E flat minor"]}, "42": {"question": "Schubert - Why was the song transposed?", "correct": "To suit a lower voice", "incorrect": ["To suit a higher voice", "Because they felt like it", "So it was more accessible to all voices"]}, "43": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas A?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["2/4", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "44": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas B?", "correct": "6/8", "incorrect": ["2/4", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "45": {"question": "Schubert - What is the meter of Stanzas C?", "correct": "2/4", "incorrect": ["6/8", "3/8", "3/4"]}, "46": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas A?", "correct": "F major", "incorrect": ["F minor", "E flat major", "G major"]}, "47": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas B?", "correct": "F minor", "incorrect": ["F major", "E flat minor", "E flat major"]}, "48": {"question": "Schubert - What is the key of Stanzas C?", "correct": "F major - F minor", "incorrect": ["E flat major - E flat minor", "G major - G minor"]}, "49": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "incorrect": ["Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "Settled, diatonic, rarely using the tonic chord"]}, "50": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "incorrect": ["Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "Flowing and carefree, often using melismas, with few leaps"]}, "51": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas A.", "correct": "Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "incorrect": ["Arpeggiated chords", "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "Flowing block chords in continuous triplet rhythm"]}, "52": {"question": "How is Schubert's type of strophic form different from simple strophic form?", "correct": "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&4, 2&5, 3&6) rather than for every stanza", "incorrect": ["Schubert uses different music for each stanza", "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&2, 3&4, 5&6) rather than for every stanza", "Schubert uses the same music for each group of stanzas (1&2&3, 4&5&6) rather than for every stanza"]}, "53": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "incorrect": ["Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "Unsettled, chromatic, infrequent key changes"]}, "54": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "incorrect": ["Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, narrow leaps (mostly descending)"]}, "55": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas B.", "correct": "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "incorrect": ["Arpeggiated chords", "Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "Detached block chords and octaves"]}, "56": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the harmony of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Sometimes irresolute (questioning)", "incorrect": ["Settled, diatonic, often using the tonic chord", "Unsettled, chromatic, frequent key changes", "Very resolute and unquestioning"]}, "57": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the melodic style of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Simple (mostly quavers, narrow pitch range) then sad (minor key, wider pitch range)", "incorrect": ["Agitated repeated notes, rising semitones, wide leaps (mostly descending)", "Flowing and carefree, often using the siciliana rhythm, with some rising leaps", "Sad (minor key, narrow pitch range) then simple (mostly quavers, wider pitch range)"]}, "58": {"question": "Schubert - Describe the accompaniment of Stanzas C.", "correct": "Arpeggiated chords", "incorrect": ["Flowing broken chords in continuous triplet rhythm", "Throbbing chords and broken octaves", "Block chords"]}}